<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Årestua Hut</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main">Jenny Creek to Årestua Hut</string>
    <string name="AxsJCrk"><b><i>Jenny Creek/Guinn Mountain Route:</i></b> November through mid April the hut is accessed from the Jenny Creek trail.
        Overnight parking is located east of the resort\'s stone wall entrance. Pass through during the ski resort\'s
        hours of operation. The approach for the winter season route is about 4.5 miles distance and 2000 feet of elevation gain.
        A track of the Jenny creek route can be obtained by clicking Jenny Creek to Årestua Hut GPS Track. <b>Know Before You Go Tip:</b>
        Current weather conditions on the highway near Nederland can be assessed from this webpage containing several webcams.
        Additional information about the Jenny Creek trail (National Forest trail #808) can be obtained from this USFS webpage.
    </string>
    <string name="AxsLake"><b><i>Lost Lake-Pipeline Route:</i></b> Throughout the entire year, the hut may be accessed via the Lost Lake-Pipeline
        route in the Indian Peaks wilderness area. <b>Summer:</b> The Lost Lake-Pipeline route is 4 miles in distance and 2000 feet in elevation gain
        <b>Winter:</b> 5 miles when the road between Eldora township and the Hessie trailhead is closed in the winter season. Users
        should be aware that the area at and above Lost Lake is known <b>avalanche</b> terrain during the winter season. To access Bryan
        Mountain, follow the old mining trail above the southeast corner of Lost lake. Expect some <i>bushwhacking</i> through the forest
        in the middle part of route. The latter part of the route is relatively level and follows the cutout through the forest
        above the natural gas pipeline. A GPS track of the Lost Lake-Pipeline route can be obtained by clicking: Lost Lake-Pipeline
        to Årestua Hut GPS Track.
    </string>
    <string name="warning">Hiking and trekking are potentially dangerous. There is the possibility of bodily injury or death. You are solely
        responsible for learning good wilderness trekking techniques, including those for emergency situations, and for exercising
        good and prudent judgement when hiking and trekking.
    </string>
    <string name="title_activity_main2">WARNING:</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main3">Lost Lake Route to Årestua Hut</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main4">CMC Boulder Group</string>
    <string name="hut"><b><i>Årestua Hut</i></b></string>
    <string name="genInfo"><b><i>General Info:</i></b> Owned and administrated by the Boulder Group of the Colorado Mountain Club (303-554-7688),
        under agreement with the U.S. Forest Service, Roosevelt National Forest district. David Miller is the present volunteer Hutmeister,
        maintaining the calendar and coordinating seasonal preparation and upkeep of the Årestua Hut. The Boulder Group built the Årestua Hut
        (aka Guinn Mt. Cabin) in 1969, a cozy and secluded relative of the better-known Brainard Lake Cabin. The Årestua Hut is located at
        11,000 feet on the north side of Guinn Mountain, and provides a winter shelter for Nordic &amp; Backcountry skiers, snowshoers, and shelter
        for summer hikers from afternoon rainshowers. The Årestua Hut has breathtaking views of the Front Range and the high plains.</string>
    <string name="ADA"><b>** Alternative formats of this information are available on request to people with disabilities.**</b></string>
    <string name="EOP">In accordance with the Federal law and U.S. Department of Agriculture policy, this institution is prohibited from
        discriminating on the basis of race, color, national origin, sex, age or disability. (Not all prohibited bases apply to all programs.)
        To file a complaint of discrimination: write USDA, Director,Office of Civil Rights, Room 326-W, Whitten Building, 1400 Independence
        Avenue SW, Washington, D.C. 20250-9410 or call (202) 720-5964 (voice and TDD). USDA is an equal opportunity provider and employer.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main5">Equal Opportunity Provider</string>
    <string name="copyRight">© 1996 – 2018 Colorado Mountain Club, All Rights Reserved</string>
    <string name="questions">Any other questions? Send an email to the Cabin Committee:  cabins@cmcboulder.org</string>
    <string-array name="links">
        <item>http://www.cmcboulder.org/cabin-brainard.html</item>
        <item>http://www.the-webcam-network.com/Colorado-USA/Eldora/2978764.html</item>
        <item>http://www.fs.usda.gov/recarea/arp/recreation/hiking/recarea/?recid=28286&amp;actid=91</item>
        <item>http://calendar.yahoo.com/arestuahut</item>
        <item>https://www.fs.usda.gov/arp</item>
        <item>https://www.fs.usda.gov/alerts/arp/alerts-notices</item>
        <item>https://www.eldora.com/the-mountain/snow-grooming-report/</item>
        <item>http://www.mountain-forecast.com/peaks/James-Peak/forecasts/3500/</item>
        <item>http://avalanche.state.co.us/forecasts/backcountry-avalanche/front-range/</item>
        <item>http://www.avalanche.org/accidents.php?date=2001–2002/</item>
        <item>http://www.summitpost.org/rollins-pass-eldora-to-fraser-or-winter-park-ski-traverse/929761/</item>
        <item>https://www.colorado.gov/dola/search-and-rescue-fund/</item>
        <item>http://www.cmcboulder.org/cabin-arestua.html?media=mobile/</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="AmenitiesWoodStove">
        Wood stove- The hut has a wood-fired stove, proven to warm the cabin on the coldest winter nights
        (where the outside temperature on windy Guinn mountain can get below -20 F). A supply of wood is prepared each
        autumn for the winter season. Overnight visitors are advised to bring fire-starting essentials for the stove.
        It helps to keep the door open when lighting the stove. The door should be shut soon after a fire is burning,
        so that the stove will run more efficiently. Once the door is shut, the slider on the bottom of the door may be
        adjusted to control the burn rate.
    </string>
    <string name="AmenitiesFires">
        Fires: Please do not create fires or construct a fire ring near the hut as this goes against our operating permit
        with the Forest Service. A fire extinguisher is provided at the hut in the event of issues with the wood stove,
        cooking of food, or should you encounter a nearby fire. Additional information is provided here for those that may
        be traveling through the nearby wilderness areas. Note that Stage 1 and Stage 2 fire restrictions do not apply the
        hut (which uses an indoor wood stove, with a spark arrestor installed). Those camping in the nearby Indian Peaks or
        James Peak wilderness areas may wish to consult the USDA Forest Service website regarding fire restriction orders
        and maps by clicking: Forest Service. Active advisories will be listed in the “Alerts and Warnings" box on the right.
    </string>
    <string name="AmenitiesWater">
        Potable Water: During the winter season, water is obtained by melting the snow around the cabin. Snow
        melting does not require treating the water, if brought to a rolling boil for 3 minutes. For additional information
        on water and its treatment in the Rocky Mountain backcountry, can be accessed by clicking: CDC). Some visitors may
        prefer to bring a water filter to remove contamination (pine needles or soot deposited from the cabin stove). During
        the summer season, the closest water source is roughly one half mile east along the Guinn mountain trail at the
        springs near the base of the steep uphill to Guinn mountain (look near N39.93955 W105.63489 at 10,665 ft elevation).
        Visitors often find the trek to obtain water in the summer does limit summer visits to the hut.
        Food and cooking: While the wood stove works well for warming the hut and melting snow, it is not sufficient for cooking.
        Overnight visitors are advised to bring a separate backpacking stove for meals. A basic supply of cookware (pans, dishes,
        and mugs) and eating utensils is stored at the hut. Please do not leave food at the hut (mice).
    </string>
    <string name="SolarPanel">
        Solar panel, LED lights, and USB charger: The CMC is grateful to the OG Power Station company in Boulder for donating an LED
        light system, supported by a solar panel and battery. To be prepared for travel to a remote wilderness location, and because
        prolonged winter weather can drain the light system, all visitors are advised to bring an emergency light (headlamp). PLEASE
        DO NOT BRING CANDLES TO THE HUT. The electrical system may also be used to charge devices from the dual USB outlet. To prevent
        draining the battery during extended bad weather, the 120V AC outlet is normally disabled except for work projects (using power
        tools) at the hut. Please always leave the two big red switches “on”. [Page 1 of 2]
    </string>
    <string name="SolarPanel2">
        They are designed to separately disconnect the solar panel or battery for maintenance or in the event of an emergency. The system
        will give a warning if the battery voltage becomes too low (9.5V DC on the meter above the USB outlet). The system will automatically
        shut down for lower voltage (7V DC) to prevent damage to the battery. Please email the Hutmeister in either event. The solar panel
        will not work if it is covered by snow or shaded by a snow drift. The effectiveness of the panel is greatly reduced even when it is
        partly covered by snow - for example, just the bottom row of cells. Please remember to clean the entire panel (use a broom) and create
        an adequate cutout in the drift (shovel is OK) on the roof (free from shadows through the day) before you leave. Small amounts of ice
        may melt off if snow is removed from the panel. If there is substantial snow accumulation, the chimney may need to be unblocked too!
        (or it will smoke out the cabin).
        [Page 2 of 2]
    </string>
    <string name="Outhouse">
        Outhouse: A separate primitive outhouse is located southeast of the hut. After each use, each user should remember to add a scoop
        of sawdust to the outhouse to aid the composting process. Two signs that can be seen from the east deck of the hut indicate the
        location of the outhouse. As a reminder please do not pee elsewhere near the cabin, because that area is the source of the snow to
        melt for drinking water. Overnight visitors are advised to bring their own toilet paper for the outhouse facility to be sure paper
        is present.
    </string>
    <string name="DoorLatch">
        Door and latch: The hut door features a weighted self-closing mechanism. The door also features a freeze resistant traditional latch
        in the style of other Nordic huts. The mechanical nature of the latch mechanism can malfunction in cold weather, potentially locking
        you out. In such a situation, in order to discourage breaking the door, access the cabin via the window as alternate entrance (the window
        lock has been removed for just this situation). Please email the Hutmeister if you encounter any problems with the door.
    </string>
    <string name="Rules">
        The guidance for visitors posted at the hut is also listed here for reference. In addition to these rules, visitors are
        reminded of the general guidance to act as good stewards of the hut. For example, please shovel snow off of the east deck to limit its
        weight and prevent damage to the deck.
            ************************************************
            DO NOT LEAVE A FIRE IN THE WOOD STOVE
            ***COOK STOVES MAY ONLY BE USED ON THE PROTECTED KITCHEN COUNTER TOP
            ***DO NOT SPLIT OR CHOP FIREWOOD IN THE HUT OR ON THE PORCH
            ***SUMMER USERS MAY NOT USE FIREWOOD; IT IS PREPARED FOR WINTER USE
            ***USE THE OUTHOUSE: DO NOT POLLUTE THE SNOW (THE SOURCE FOR DRINKING WATER IN THE WINTER)
            ***DO NOT DISPOSE OF TRASH IN THE OUTHOUSE
            ***PACK OUT WHAT YOU PACK IN
            ***DO NOT LEAVE FOOD, BECAUSE OF MICE
            ***BEFORE YOU LEAVE, CLEAN AND TIDY UP FOR THE NEXT GROUP, AND TO PREVENT MICE
            ***USE FEE: $1/DAY, $5/NIGHT, PER PERSON
            ************************************************
    </string>
    <string name="FS_Permit">
        The original “conditions of occupancy and use for the Guinn mountain hut” are reproduced here to document
        and summarize the operating agreement: “In accordance with the special use permit issued to the Colorado Mountain Club on
        June 24, 1969, and the regulations of the Secretary of Agriculture (36 C.F.R. 251.24 and 251.25), the following conditions of occupancy
        and use for the Guinn Mountain Hut are hereby established: No person, party, or organization shall occupy said hut for more than
        three consecutive nights. The use of said hut shall be available to the general public as well as the Colorado Mountain Club members
        on a first-come first-served basis. No reservations are required or permitted. All non-burnable refuse shall be removed from the
        national Forest. Garbage or trash shall not be buried." [Page 1 of 2]
        </string>
    <string name="FS_Permit2">
    "First Aid and other emergency equipment provided and maintained by the Colorado Mountain Club shall be used only when appropriate and necessary.
    Open fires are not permitted within three hundred yards of said hut except in the stone and concrete fireplace provided and maintained by the
    Colorado Mountain Club. Use only dead or downed timber for firewood. No fireworks or firearms may be stored within three hundred yards of said
    hut except in the stone and concrete fireplace provided and maintained by the Colorado Mountain Club. The conditions are necessary to promote
    public health, safety, welfare, and convenience. A violation may result in a fine not more than $500.00 and imprisonment for not more than
    six months, or both.”
    Signed Frauz Mohling, President Colorado Mountain Club-Boulder Group; Signed K. Kelso, Roosevelt National Forest Ft. Collins, Colorado
    dated February 16, 1970 [Page 2 of 2]
    </string>
    <string name="Snow_WeatherReportsDayUse"> \Snow&amp;Weather Reports: Eldora Ski Resort is the nearest winter trailead: Eldora Snow Report.
        James peak weather report (nearest proxy near the hut): James peak weather.
        Colorado avalanche conditions: CAIC.
        Skiing and Recreation
        Day visits: In the winter, the hut is often used as a day destination for skiers using the Jenny Creek route. The trails are marked
        (blue diamonds and signs) and you will typically find the trail broken in by hut visitors. Recent snowstorms or snow drifting from the
        wind may, however, require trail breaking along any section of the approach. Even a day visit is a worthy and rewarding trip. Day
        users should keep an eye out for highlights along the trail, including views of the mountains ahead along the downhill section from Eldora,
        the icy (in winter) section along Jenny creek, the natural tunnel of trees at the end of one of the biggest uphill sections, and the ruins of
        the miner\'s cabin near the crux uphill onto Guinn mountain.
    </string>
    <string name="DayTrips">
        Day destinations from the hut: It\'s well worth starting your trip early enough in the day to venture above the hut. Great views of landmarks
        including James Peak, Needles Eye tunnel, Yankee Doodle lake, and South Arapaho peak can be taken in from the summit of Guinn mountain or the
        ridge to Hell Hill. The view of the sunset on James peak is memorable from Guinn mountain, but don’t forget the shadow of the Continental Divide
        is cast early in the winter. Yankee Doodle lake, Jenny lake, and Forest lakes off of Rollins Pass road are good day destinations for those making
        an extended stay at the hut. Visitors should expect to find the infamous winds of Indian Peaks wilderness are a true equalizer relative to the
        coldest US winter locations, and are reminded to bring plenty of clothing to stay warm and prevent frostbite.
    </string>

    <string name="BackcountryUse">
        Backcountry use: Backcountry skiing may be found near the hut, e.g., the southeast side of Guinn mountain. The south facing gully between Guinn
        and Bryan mountains offers a ~1000’ descent from the Pipeline trail to Jenny creek. Bryan mountain has become a popular backcountry destination.
        Skiers are reminded that the high altitude area near the hut contains avalanche terrain. For example, on November 28, 2001 one of two skiers were
        drowned after being swept under the ice by an avalanche while descending the steep slopes above Yankee Doodle Lake. A report on that incident may
        be accessed, by clicking: avalanche.org.
    </string>
    <string name="Emergencies">
        In the Event of Emergency: Intermittent cellular phone service (including an internet connection to this webpage) may be achieved at the hut through
        the tower at nearby Bryan Mountain. The quality of connection typically does not improve higher up on the summit of Guinn Mountain. More consistent
        reception may be obtained along the Lost Lake trail closer to Bryan mountain at 1/3 mile from the hut at N39.94273 W105.63914 at 10,956 ft.
        In the event of an emergency, visitors are advised to have a communications liaison go to the above location and dial 911 to reach the Boulder county
        or Gilpin County sheriff office, or be forwarded to Search And Rescue.
        Information regarding Colorado Outdoor Recreation Search and Rescue and related membership may be accessed by clicking: CORSAR. Consider a membership
        or donation as CORSAR receives limited public funds to support its operations.
    </string>
    <string name="ContinentalDivide">
         Eldora-Winter Park/Frasier traverse: The hut may be used as a base camp or as a resting point for those
        touring between Eldora and Winter Park. Information on the long ski touring routes crossing the Continental Divide may be obtained by clicking:
        Touring Information. Visitors should expect to find the infamous winds of Indian Peaks wilderness are a true equalizer relative to the coldest US
        winter locations, and are reminded to bring plenty of clothing to stay warm and prevent frostbite.
    </string>
    <string name="Dogs">
        Because the area near the hut is commonly sourced for the snow melted for drinking water, it is requested that visitors not bring their dogs to
        the hut during the winter season, which runs from November 1 through May 31.  Moose tracks have also been seen on the Jenny Creek trail in winter.
        Moose and dogs don\'t mix!  Meese are bigger and don\'t like being bothered! :)
    </string>
    <string name="LostFoundAndEvents">
        Lost and Found: Occasionally there are items that get left at the hut. Inquire about lost and found items with the Hutmeister.
        Upkeep and Events: The hut is solely maintained by users and volunteers (i.e., YOU!).
        The suggested donation to cover maintenance costs and the supplies related to operation of the hut is: Day Use $1, Overnight $5 per person.
        No cash? Donate on PayPal via email to brainardcabin [at] gmail [dot] com. Please note \'To Arestua hut\' in your PayPal donation to make
        it easier to recognize, and to put your donation towards the cabin. PLEASE attend the fall work party to prepare firewood and ready the hut
        for use through the following year. Contact the Hutmeister (arestuahut [at] yahoo.com) for an invitation, take an information card (available
        near the donations box at the hut), or add your own email to a card and leave it in the donations box. Each year there are typically a few
        separate days in the summer or early autumn related to specific projects at the hut.
    </string>
    <!--activity titles-->
    <string name="title_activity_main6">Amenities-Wood stove</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main7">Amenities-Fires&amp;Restrictions</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main8">Amenities-Water&amp;Cooking</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main9">SolarPanel</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main10">Backcountry Use</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main11">Outhouse</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main12">Door and Latch</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main13">Rules of Use</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main14">Forest Service Permit</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main15">Snow and Local Weather</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main16">Continental Divide Traverse</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main17">Lost &amp;Found, Volunteering</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main18">Dogs are great except when...</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main19">Forest Service Permit</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main20">Day Trips</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main21">Emergencies</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main22">Solar Panel</string>
</resources>
